传说这是不可能发生的
They said it couldn't be done...
阿尔茜身手敏捷 神出鬼没
the one called "Arcee" is too quick
根本无法擒获
too stealthy to be captured.
不过 现在你却来到了此地
Well, here you are
还得到了创造历史的机会
with a rare opportunity to make history.
你知道 我截获了一段汽车人的加密信息
You see, I have intercepted this encrypted Autobot signal
既然是加密信息
and if it's encrypted
就一定有重要内容
it must be important.
替我解开密文 我就给你个痛快的死法
Decode it for me, and I will see to it that you perish quickly.
大声点！哭哭啼啼地我听不见你在说些什么
Speak up. I can't hear you when you whimper.
去死吧
Get... fragged.
或许要让你屈服
Perhaps you will be more inclined to cooperate
得找另外的人来受罪
when it is not your own well-being at stake.
阿尔茜 好久不见
Arcee. Been a while.
告诉我加密代码
Give me the encryption code
否则你的同伴飞过山\N就要下去跟汽车人尸骨堆做伴了
or I will add your comrade Cliffjumper to the multitude of fallen Autobots below.
让他死好了 我跟他不熟
Scrap him. I barely know the guy.
噢 你伤害了我敏感的心
Ouch. Glad I'm not the sensitive type.
如今的塞博特恩 已经和一个大坟场毫无二致
Cybertron is little more than a graveyard now.
告诉我密码！
Give me the code!
我不怕你 红蜘蛛
I'm not afraid of you, Starscream.
你不是威震天
You're no Megatron.
才三步 隔板？
Three steps, Bulkhead?
你就只能走这么远？
That's all you can manage?
对不起神子 我的腿还疼着呢
I'm sorry, Miko. My legs still hurt.
我怎么跟你说的？
What did I tell you?
没有借口
"No excuses."
没错 再来一次
Exactly. Try again.
这次要迈十步
10 steps this time.
我希望铁堡数据库解码的进展
I hope decoding the Iacon database
能比隔板康复得更顺利一些
is going more smoothly than Bulkhead's recovery.
缓慢 但是稳定 我的老朋友
Slow but steady, old friend.
啊 人类科技！
Agh. Human technology.
不过你在这一领域的专长
But your expertise in the field should provide any edge
应该能让我们在这场竞赛中领先于霸天虎
we need to beat the Decepticons at this game.
恐怕他们凭借塞博特恩的科技也不会落后到哪儿去
I fear their access to Cybertronian technology
may provide them with equal advantage.
还不够好！
Not good enough!
你得要比以前更强壮
You have to come back stronger than before!
你得休息一会儿了 隔板
Time for a break, Bulkhead.
休息？
A break?
你觉得在交火中 虎子们会让隔板休息吗？
You think the 'Cons are gonna give Bulkhead a break in the middle of a fire fight?!
你要是把病人逼得太紧
If you push a patient too far too fast
有可能加重伤情
you risk exacerbating their injuries.
可是…
But...
隔板该休息了
Bulkhead needs to rest.
让开！
Out of the way!
神子
Miko?
哦呃 嘿 阿尔茜 我只是在…
Oh. Uh... hey, Arcee. I was just...
是不是离悬崖太近了？
Are we a little close to the edge?
我不怕高
Heights don't scare me.
隔板恢复得不错
Bulkhead's coming along just fine.
这大部分都是你的功劳
Thanks mostly to your efforts.
但是他现在需要的是朋友
But he needs a friend right now
而不是操练官
not a drill sergeant.
不好意思 我上来是想找点私人空间
No offense, but I came up here for some privacy.
我明白你的感受
I understand what you're going through.
你要是想找人聊聊…
If you ever want someone to talk to...
我很好 行了吧？
I'm fine, okay?
硬壳差点杀死的不是我
I'm not the one Hardshell tried to scrap.
神子 你在乎的人受了伤 这的确令人难过
Miko, it's rough when someone you care about gets hurt.
但封闭自己的感情 无济于事
Closing yourself off from feeling... won't help anyone.
好吧 就像你明白似的？
Well, you would know, wouldn't you?
是的
Yes...
我明白
I would.
阿尔茜 很抱歉
Arcee, I'm sorry.
我不是故意提起的
I didn't mean that.
没关系 最近我正好在想他
It's okay. He's... been on my mind lately.
我 失去挡板之后
After I lost my first partner, Tailgate
远离了所有人
I pushed everyone away.
直到飞过山出现了
Until Cliffjumper came along.
他是什么样的人？
What was he like?
小飞他… 很健谈
Cliff was... quite the conversationalist.
飞过山 你怎…
Cliffjumper, are you...?
我… 我没想到你真的关心我
I... I can't... I can't believe you actually care.
我只关心你还能不能讲话 你讲了
The only thing I care about is whether you talked just now.
你对来救你的人都是这种态度吗？
Are you always this nice to your rescuers?
你没回答我的问题
Didn't answer my question.
我厌倦了红蜘蛛小儿科般的拷问
I got bored with Starscream's little workout.
于是我关闭了引擎 假装昏了过去
So I idled my engines and faked shutdown.
小红信了
Scream bought it.
你怎么被抓来的？
How did you wind up here?
我截获了霸天虎的通讯 听说他们在母星上有所行动
Intercepted some chatter about a Decepticon operation on the old home planet.
我一路跟踪 发现红蜘蛛
So I followed the trail and found Starscream
从这里将大批能量运往塞博特恩
shipping massive amounts of Energon here to Cybertron.
你呢？
What's your story?
一样
Same.
你还真健谈
You're quite the conversationalist.
各种审讯方式我都试过了 都不管用
I've tried every interrogation technique, and nothing is working.
要不是因为他们带着重要的密码 我早就杀了他们
I would just eliminate them, but the code they carry is too valuable.
要是我能直接打开他们拿到密码就好了
If only I could break them open and just take it!
不 我不会把犯人送到地面上的！
No, I will not take the prisoners to the surface!
为什么要让他抢我的功劳？
Why should I let him have all the glory?
他们带着重要的密码
The code they carry is too valuable.
好吧 反正我也得把能量送给他
All right, since I must deliver the Energon to him anyway...
这里就是卡隆？
So, this is Kaon, huh?
我真喜欢你们经营的这个地方
Love what you Decepticons have done with the place.
这些废墟真是生机勃勃
The ruins are especially picturesque.
安静！
Silence!
我们到了…
Here we are.
这… 不是个好兆头
That's not a good sign.
既然我没法强迫你们说出加密代码
Since I could not compel you to surrender the encryption code
我只好把你们交给手段更加…
I'm forced to introduce you to someone whose methods are a little more...
有说服力的人
persuasive.
我们可能比我预想的还要惨
We may be in a little more trouble than I thought.
汽车人 来跟震荡波打个招呼吧
Autobots, say hello to Shockwave.
送出高如小山的能量
Delivering a mountain of Energon
截取了汽车人的加密电报
intercepting an encrypted Autobot communicate?
还捕获了两个关键的俘虏 我承认这是很大的功劳
and capturing two key prisoners is impressive, I admit.
不过威震天陛下对他副手的要求比这…
But lord Megatron expects nothing less from his first lieu...
…我是不是该让你开始工作了？
I should let you work, right?
看来你需要专注 继续吧…
No doubt you are trying to concentrate. Carry on.
震荡波 你确信能成功提取加密代码
Um, Shockwave, are you certain you can extract the decryption code
而不是毁掉这个人的神经系统吗？
without first nullifying our subject's neural net?
大脑神经接入器是我发明的
I invented the cortical psychic patch.
我很清楚它的特性
I am familiar with its idiosyncrasies.
这是当然
Of course you are.
别拿着那东西靠近我 你这个独眼怪物！
Keep that thing away from me, you one-eyed freak!
放开她 冲我来！
Leave her alone! Use it on me!
别担心
Do not worry.
要是她的神经承受不了这个过程
If her mind does not survive the procedure
下一个就是你
you will be next.
啊 密码…
Ah. The code.
阿尔茜 阿尔茜！我要杀了你们两个！
Arcee. Arcee! I'll scrap you both!
闭嘴！我在听！
Shut up! I'm trying to listen!
我是擎天柱
This is Optimus Prime.
至所有收到这条信息的汽车人
To all surviving Autobots who hear this message
我邀请你们到银河系一个偏远的角落来与我会合
I ask you to join me in a remote corner of the galaxy.
这是一个充满能量的小星球
on a small planet rich with Energon.
我有理由推断
I have reason to believe this\Nworld will soon
这里很快就会成为霸天虎新的侵略目标
become a new target of Decepticon conquest.
我的队伍小而精悍
Our team is small but strong.
到这些坐标来与我会合 以便策划抵抗运动
Join me at these coordinates so that we might plan our resistance.
一路平安
Safe journeys.
啊 干得漂亮！
Aha! Brilliant!
现在我们不但知道擎天柱的位置
Not only do we know where to find Optimus Prime
还知道他在求援
but he's begging for help.
这正是突击的好时机！
Now is the time to strike!
你没有利用价值了…
You are no longer of use.
嘿 小红 我很好奇
Hey, Scream. Curious...
你总是让别的虎子帮你下手吗？
you always let other Cons do your dirty work?
震荡波！你已经杀掉了一个我的俘虏
Shockwave! You already disposed of one of my prisoners.
飞过山是我的
Cliffjumper is mine.
你的想法很不合逻辑
Your reasoning is hardly... logical.
不过请自便
But indulge yourself.
你觉得怎样 飞过山？
What do you think, Cliffjumper?
这里的选择多种多样
Plenty to choose from here.
我们是要精确的对半开呢？
Shall we go with precise dissection
还是钝器呢？
or blunt force?
随你选 小红 不管你选什么
Your choice, Scream. Whatever you pick
最终都是我用在你身上
I'm just gonna end up using it on you.
好吧
Very well.
要不我们来用最传统的方法
Why don't we do this the old-fashioned way?
不 不！
No! No!!
多谢相救
Thanks for the save.
该你说了 红蜘蛛
Your turn, Starscream.
能量是用来做什么的？
What's with all the Energon?
我怎么会告诉你
As if I would tell you!
你不说 就用你做实验 我没有开玩笑！
Talk, or you're a science experiment. I'm not kidding!
你最好告诉她点东西
You should probably tell her something.
我不确定我能拖住她多久
I'm not sure how long I can hold her back.
这方面我不是专家
I'm no expert with this thing
不过我知道 只要手一滑 就能烧毁整个神经系统
but I hear one slip-up can fry a neural net.
震荡波！你们该找的是他！
Shockwave! He's the one you want!
他正在卡隆地下建造一个太空桥！
He's building a Space Bridge beneath Kaon.
不可能
Impossible.
太空桥技术已经失传好几个兆周了！
Space bridge technology's been lost for mega-cycles.
但是他做到了！
And yet he managed!
震荡波从不离开塞博特恩 正是因为他能回收到零件
Shockwave never left Cybertron precisely so he could scavenge parts
并且通过反向工程研究出太空桥的原理！
and reverse-engineer space bridge mechanics!
你送来的能量刚好够他启动太空桥的！
And you just delivered all the Energon he needs to power it up.
是的 虽然这么做令我煎熬\N不过我还是尝试着合作 呃！
While it often pains me, I try to be a team player.
你去哪儿？
Going somewhere?
去摧毁太空桥
To take down a space bridge.
不带上我吗？
Without me?
这个行动需要隐蔽
This'll require stealth/
而不是…闲扯
Not... chatter.
你说的闲扯分散了红蜘蛛的注意力 好让你有时间挣脱
Oh, you mean the chatter that distracted Starscream long enough for you to free yourself?
别拖我后腿就成！
Just try not to slow me down.
你知道怎么走吗？
You know where you're going?
我所在的部队曾经利用这些坑道活动
My unit used these tunnels during the war.
这是旧塞博特恩的一部分
They're part of old Cybertron.
我们早点毁掉太空桥
The sooner we blow the bridge
就能早点与擎天柱会合
the sooner we join up with Optimus Prime.
代我向他问好
Give him my regards.
你没听到擎天柱的信息吗？
Did you not hear Prime's message?
他需要我们！
He needs us.
我不擅长团队合作
Teamwork isn't my thing.
我们了结这件事之后
after we finish this
你我各奔东西
you and I go our separate ways.
你说了算 搭档
Whatever you say, partner.
把话说清楚
Let's get one thing straight...
你不是我的搭档！
you are not my partner.
阿尔茜 我明白这不好受 真的
Arcee, I know it's rough. I really do.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
挡板
Tailgate.
挡板！
Tailgate!
封闭自己的感情
Closing yourself off from feeling...
- 无济于事\N- 无济于事
- won't help anyone.\N- won't help anyone.
听着耳熟
Sounds familiar.
那是个好建议
Good advice is good advice.
我想知道 接下来怎样了？
So, I got to know... what happened next?
震荡波的最新杰作
Shockwave's latest work of art.
我已经感觉它要吸进去东西了
Already fueled and ready to rip.
阿尔茜 看那个眼熟吗？
Arcee... look familiar?
擎天柱提供的坐标
The coordines Optimus provided.
太空桥的目的地已经指向了那里
They're being used to target the space bridge.
这意味着虎子们将会偷袭擎天柱的队伍
Which means the 'Cons will ambush Optimus
赶在汽车人的援军到达之前
and his team. before any Autobot reinforcements can get there.
要是虎子们杀害了擎天柱
If the 'Cons scorch Optimus
战争必败无疑
the war is as good as over.
我们能挽救这一切
We can fix that.
不行 我们的能力不足以摧毁太空桥
No. We don't have the ordnance to blow the bridge.
我得想办法破坏控制系统
I'll have to sabotage the control systems.
怎么做？
What about access?
你打算走上去向他们寻求许可吗？
You just gonna walk up and ask for permission?
不 是你去
No... you are.
啊 不好意思
Uh, excuse me.
我从观光团掉队了
I got separated from the tour group.
你们知道怎么去霸天虎基地吗？
Does anyone know where I can find the Decepticon base?
喔 红蜘蛛指挥官没有跟你们说过吗？
Whoa! Didn't Commander Starscream tell you?
我现在是你们一边的了
I'm on your side now.
那个胆小鬼擎天柱夹着尾巴溜了
That coward Optimus Prime turned tail and ran.
留下我们这些汽车人自求多福
Left the rest of us Autobots to fend for ourselves.
毫无同伴情谊 哼
So much for comraderie, huh?
我想我还是加入胜利者的队伍好了
Figured I'd rather be on the winning team.
于是接受了红蜘蛛的招安
So I took Starscream up on his offer.
猜猜看擎天柱看到\N满天霸天虎降落时是什么表情！
Imagine the look on Prime's face when it starts raining Decepticons...
我也在其中！
me with them.
看 我知道红蜘蛛的所有计划
Really, I know all about Starscream's plan.
我们会相处得很好的
We can all get along now.
有人在我身后 是吧？
There's... someone behind me, isn't there?
只有红蜘蛛才会在处决手无寸铁的囚犯时失手！
Only Starscream could fail to dispose of a helpless captive.
嗯 那是正常工作的声音吗？
Uh... is it supposed to sound like that?
闯入者！
Interloper!
你改写了能量容载的程序 对吧？
You have overridden the Energon-containment protocols, haven't you?
很聪明 不过我能修好！
Clever, but not irreversible.
要摧毁一个神经系统有很多方法
There is more than one way to nullify a neural net.
这次你别想！
Not this time.
小飞？
Cliff?
我就知道你关心我！
I knew you cared.
看来震荡波的自大出卖了他
It appears Shockwave's arrogance was his undoing.
摧毁他们！
Destroy them!
汽车人 不管你们对太空桥做了什么
Autobots... whatever you did to the space bridge
快撤消！
undo it now!
他们要是真想向我们寻求帮助 就应该停火
They should really stop shooting at us if they want our help.
眼下我们的退路已经被阻断了
Seeing as how our exit is blocked
而正好有个太空桥的传送门指向擎天柱的位置
and we have an open space bridge portal currently set for Prime's location...
你跟我来吗？
You with me?
太空桥 快爆炸了！
The space bridge... it's going to blow!
有什么能耐都使出来吧！
Give it everything you got!
正中红心！
Bull's-Eye!
你觉得震荡波还活着吗？
Think Shockwave survived?
最好还活着 我要再和他较量一番！
Hope so. I want a rematch.
我们去找擎天柱吧 搭档
Let's find Optimus... partner.
充满能量 嗯？
Rich with Energon, huh?
但愿整块石头不全是这番光景
Hope the whole rock doesn't look like this.
这让我想起当年我在锈海迷失的时候
Reminds me of the time I was lost in the Sea of Rust
（Sea of rust 锈海 由星球上不稳定化学物质\N所构成的海洋 位于塞博特恩赤道)
在塞博特恩
back on Cybertron
不过那次我脱离了部队 连一个说话的人都没有！
except I was separated from my unit with absolutely no one to talk to.
（Sea of rust 锈海 由星球上不稳定化学物质\N所构成的海洋 位于塞博特恩赤道)
Talk at?
是喋喋不休吧？
承认吧 你喜欢有人陪着！
Admit it... you love the company!
有趣
Funny...
一开始我觉得我不可能习惯飞过山的喋喋不休
At first, I didn't think I'd ever get used to Cliff's constant chatter.
可现在 却总是感觉过于安静了
Now... there's nothing louder to me than the silence.